# **Adrià Figueres**

# Adriafigueresgarcia@gmail.com

# **Profile**

Senior PHP developer specialized in back-end developments, with a strong focus on quality, improving the processes and practices of the teams where I am involved. Having more than 5 years of experience, my goal is not just delivering working software but consolidating solid architectures and optimizing the maintainability of the final result.

# **Core strengths**

- In-depth understanding of Object-Oriented principles
- Passionate about Clean Code and Agile principles
- Good organizational skills; focused on getting results
- Team worker, always open to discussion
- Continuous and quick learner

### **Technical skills**

### PHP ecosystem

- PHP 5.4 to 8.1
- Frameworks: Symfony 4.4 to 5.4, Laravel 6, CodeIgniter 3
- Other libraries: Symfony Console Component, Symfony Finder component, Twig, Faker, SwiftMailer, EmailValidator, PHPDotenv
- Testing: PHPUnit, SeleniumHQ, Behat
- Static analysis tools: PHPStan
- Development Tools: PHPStorm, Visual Studio Code, Postman
- Integrations: Apache, Nginx

#### Software architecture

- Web Services: SOAP protocol and REST architectural style
- Patterns: Adapter, MVC, Hexagonal Architecture
- Solution architecture: UML

# **Data Processing**

- Relational Databases: MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL
- NoSQL: MongoDB
- Message Formats: XML (including XSD, XSLT), JSON

#### **Miscellaneous**

- Front End: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery
- Agile methodologies: SCRUM, TDD, BDD, Refactoring
- Continuous integration: Git, SVN, Jenkins, Stash
- Virtualization: Docker Code reviews: GitHub
- Management tools: JIRA, Confluence, Figma, Microsoft Office
- Other languages: JAVA, JavaScript backend

# **Work experience**

### May 2022 to present: Software Engineer at Bodas.net

<u>Bodas.net</u> is the leading wedding portal in the world, helping couples in love to organize their wedding.

- Creating solid architecture for the project to minimize the effort
- Implemented BDD, involving QA analysts and product analysts in the process
- Created thorough documentation, focusing on practical aspects to facilitate incorporation of new developers to the team
- Led presentations (technical and sprint reviews) to the business
- Coordinated with a development team based in the USA

### Jan 2021 to May 2022: Senior backend Developer at **Bodas.net**

- Migrated much of the legacy code to Hexagonal Architecture in order to be maintainable, scalable and testable
- Improved development processes and guidelines in the team, using Clean Code, refactoring, code reviews and static analysis tools as techniques to reduce the technical debt
- Fostered the use of testing techniques, achieving a test coverage increase from 20% to 95%
- Constantly managing third party APIs with Postman
- Coordinated tasks in a squad composed of four developers, being responsible for integrating all the branches in master after code reviews
- Designed and maintained relational data models, optimizing consistency and performance
- Trained and supervised newly incorporated programmers

### Feb 2020 to Oct 2020: Mid-level web developer at Azertium IT

Azertium IT is a technological company of Consulting and Integral ICT Services

- Developed and maintained brand new projects from 0 for important Spanish banks as Caixa bank
- Had plenty responsibility as a one-man project
- Reported every week about the job done and show the following road map to my superiors through presential meetings and self-made documentation
- Discussed in one on one with client about pros and cons of new features
- Implemented all the project following the SOLID principles and TDD
- Acted as a bridge between the customers and the company from a technical perspective

#### May 2018 to Jan 2020: Mid-level web developer at ACAI performance

ACAI performance is a start-up marketing agency, experts in lead and client generation techniques

- Developer new features in ACAI web portals
- Created our own API REST in order to implement for our clients
- Decided, made and planned tasks directly with the CEO
- Took responsibility of all the IT implementations of the company between 2 people

### Early career

#### March 2016 to Apr 2018: Junior web developer in NexTReT for TV3

TV3 is the most important Spanish regional television channel that broadcasts in Catalonia

• Development, design and testing of PHP web portals under Linux environment for projects in the CCMA portals

#### Oct 2015 to March 2016: Junior Application developer in NexTReT

IT company dedicated to the optimization and monitoring of the ICT area of their clients

• Development of adaptative and corrective applications for monitoring web pages and mobile apps with Selenium Robot framework and Chromedriver testing with JAVA

### **Education**

- Certificate of Higher Education in CAD (Cross-platform Application Development)
- First Certificate of Cambridge in English